Heiwa Fansubs Presents:
"Great Detective Conan"
"Challenge to Kudo Shin'ichi"
Somehow... my body's gone numb...
- Ran!
Oi, are you okay?!
"If not given an antidote in time..."
"...she will die."
Ran!
Boy detective! Not yet?
You don't know yet?!
Cabaret club...
What about a cabaret club?!
There's only 40 seconds left.
That's it!
I've got it.
This is...
Stop this already! What is this?!
Anyhow, weren't you throwing
loving glances at Sensei to try and use him?
Not really.
Unlike a certain somebody,
I don't want to spread my body around.
If you wanna deal in the sex trade,
I can grant your wish.
You're gonna be Number 2 for life, aren't ya?
Crap woman! I'll kill ya!
Kyoko! Stop it!
Lemme go, I said!
I told all of you this, didn't I?
I won't allow anyone to come between
me and Sensei.
He's...
...my trophy.
Sensei.
Huh? What is it?
I have tomorrow off.
Ah, I see...
Do you have any plans?
Should I...
come over to Sensei's home again?
Ah... I wouldn't mind...
Really?
- Kanpai!
Damn...
He's monopolizing Kumi-chan.
Who on earth is that guy anyway?
When he first started coming in,
he was just a regular customer.
Then he suddenly got rich...
That crap woman!
Eh?
"Private Detective
Mori Kogoro"
Did you just say something?
That story's already over.
"'Cristano' No. 2
Kyoko"
More importantly, let's enjoy ourselves...
How cute you are!
I get that a lot.
You're the worst, Dad...
Look... Isn't it obvious your father's
a horrible cheater...
...so why are we sneaking in here
to investigate him?
This is...
This is only a major reconnaissance mission
that Mom asked us to do.
Fool! We're just here
to check up on his cheating.
If you say that,
don't bring in the police anymore.
"MPD Investigation Unit One - Takagi Wataru"
I'm sorry, Detective Takagi.
Without you, we who are under 18
couldn't get into a store like this otherwise.
So please don't get me involved in anything.
If Sato-san saw me in a place like this...
Excuse me...
"'Cristano' Hostess - Kazuyo"
Thank you for waiting. I'm Kazuyo.
Ah, sit down, sit down...
Excuse me.
Shin'ichi's Childhood Friend
Mori Ran
Ah, by the way, that man there...
He was a very popular
variety show host, wasn't he?
"Official Mnemonic Challenge"
"Beika University Science Department
Mathematics Department
Mine Masahito (Associate Professor)"
Which reminds me...
Which reminds me, he also had a book published.
Ehh... He seems to be very popular.
Thanks for waiting!
Now for the pride of this store, Game Time!
Today's game is, Kiss-Kiss Derby!
The lucky challengers are... these two!
Each challenger takes turns
receiving a kiss from...
...each of the 20 girls lined up here
who then pour wine into their glasses.
Each challenger can choose between
1 to 3 girls per turn!
Okay, let's do it!
"'Cristano' No. 1 - Kumi"
For the one who reaches me, Kumi,
with their glass of wine...
...will receive as their prize...
a kiss for a present.
Wait for me, Kumi-chan!
Because Kogoro-chan here'll be right there!
Um... How should we choose who goes
first and second? I don't mind either.
You can go first.
Well then...
Then... just one.
The first challenger
cautiously picks just one girl!
Just one? How chintzy...
Such a small person!
I... will choose 3!
Shiori-chan, Karen-chan and Haruka-chan!
- Yes!
He's suddenly chosen 3 girls!
It's an explosion of sweet kisses!
Then, I'll take two!
A flower in both hands! A double kiss!
Kogoro-san, hurry and come to me!
Of course you'll come to me, won't you?
Of course!
I'll take you on, one by one!
One after another!
These three then:
Maria-chan, Saki-chan and Anna-chan!
- Yes!
Kiss! Kiss! Kiss!
Somehow... I can't watch this anymore!
- Sir looks like he's having fun.
- I do envy him a little...
Then...
I'll take one after another, too, with three girls!
This has gotten good!
With this, that's 12!
Kogoro-ojisama, hurry and take me away.
Sure!
As a man, I can take you all on!
Rina-chan, Misako-chan and Mao-chan, you three!
They're slowly getting
closer to Kumi's lips!
15 down!
Well then...
Just one.
Ohh! Just one now!
That totals 16!
The 16th one is Kyoko-san!
She's inhaling his mouth!
Yui-chan, Shoko-chan and Nagisa-chan...
Huh? Ala?
1, 2, 3...
Too bad! There's no way you can
reach Kumi-chan now!
I was certain Sensei would come to me.
Damn!
Eh? Ah... Kumi-chan?!
- Kumi-chan!?
Everyone, please don't move!
Don't touch anything!
Detective Takagi, call the police.
Ah... yeah.
Boy detective?!
What are you doing coming here?
She's dead...
Kyaa!
I'm sorry. I lost sight of myself...
I guess she was poisoned?
Most likely the poison was put into
the wine just before she drank it...
What?! What! What! What?!
Oi! that wine... I... I drank some of that, too!?
A judge! No, a doctor! Where's a doctor?!
Ah, I feel a sudden pain...
Calm down!
If there had been poison in your wine,
you'd be in the next world already.
Oh. Ah, that's right.
Thanks to Kudo-kun, after the incident occurred,
not a single person has left this store.
Yes.
The criminal should still be among us.
Sato-san.
We've confirmed which decanter
contained the poison.
Which one was it?
Wait, boy detective!
This is an adult's society
where love and hate swirl.
A kid like you should bow out.
Kumi-chan's enemy...
This great detective, Kogoro Mori,
will surely pick them out!
From your decanter,
a component of wolfsbane was detected.
What's that?
I don't even know what that is.
You had gotten into a dispute
with the victim today.
So?
Didn't you tell her?
That you would kill her or something...
Hold on a minute!
It's true I said that, but it'd be impossible
for me to seriously kill her, now wouldn't it?!
A violent battle between women
unfolds on the battlefield for No. 1...
Doesn't that end in murder?
What's with that reasoning?
Even if I became No. 1 that way, I'd just be
arrested and it'd be over, now wouldn't it?!
Thing is, if you're gonna say such things...
...then all of the cast and store assistants
would be suspects too!
All of them?
Yes.
There isn't a single person in this store who
didn't resent or hate that crap woman.
Then why was that poison in your decanter?
I don't know about that.
I don't remember who it was that
gave me that decanter anymore...
Liar!
I'm not lying!
Excuse me.
If I recall...
...Kyoko-san, you were in this position, right?
Oi, boy detective!
What on earth is this about?!
It's important.
Please remember carefully.
Down from that woman was...
Nagisa, Shoko, and Yui.
And, I think I was probably here.
How did you end up as number 16?
How did you decide that?
No reason really.
I was always just right around that point.
I see...
Kudo-kun.
What meaning is there to position 16?
In this game,
the one who gets to 16 is the winner.
Once you get to 16, there's only 4 people left.
Since between 1 to 3 people
can be chosen in each turn...
...that leaves between 1 and 3.
You absolutely couldn't reach 20!
That's how it is.
In other words, by putting the poison
into number 16's decanter...
...you would surely kill Kumi-san.
The criminal is a logical thinker...
...and at the very least
is someone good in mathematics.
Good in mathematics...
The criminal...
...is you!
I'm the criminal because I'm good at math?
That isn't logical at all!
Thing is, I was in love with her,
so I couldn't kill her, now could I?
If you were in love with her...
...did she necessarily feel the same for you?
To Kumi-chan, maybe you were just
a good customer who punctually paid his bills...
That is definitely not true!
"Only reason makes us human."
Please excuse me for what I've done.
"Doubt is the beginning of knowledge."
There's also that quote, isn't there?
You are...
And? What did you want to ask?
Mine-san, do you know
the underlying rule of that game?
Yes.
When you put it in
numerical formula form, it's n=4-r.
n is the number that you take,
and r is the number the other person takes.
But, if a person who knows
the game's rules plays second...
...then you couldn't win against them.
Let's see... In other words...
One person in each round
can pick between 1 and 3.
Therefore, if you're in the second spot...
...you can pick a number that gives you
a multiple of 4 so that 4 is chosen each round...
Even if you say that, I don't understand it!
At any rate, if you went first,
you could win, right?
That's how it is...
Anyhow, even if you weren't a mathematician
and just gave it a little thought...
...it seems anyone could come up with
the winning strategy.
That doesn't make me the criminal.
You were at this store the entire time,
weren't you? Didn't you notice anything?
I wasn't here...
Damn...
Either Kyoko or Mine should be the criminal...
Hey! Um... It would be a problem if
you used your cell phone.
It's just a business e-mail,
so don't be a bother.
Something's... weird...
What is it?
Even though one of their friends was killed...
...none of them seems to feel sad about it...
Hey, Mao-chan, what are you doing?!
She's dead, so it's okay now, isn't it?
I don't wanna see her face even a second longer.
Wai... that's important evidence.
Weren't you told not to touch things?
Why would men want to come
to a place like this?
Why is that!?
Hey, Dad, why is it?
Oi, oi! Don't be irresponsible!
Let me go!
Now, now, stop it...
That hurt, you stupid woman...
Huh?
I can smell it...
The scent of scandal...
What are you doing there so sneakily!
What did you hide just now?!
Don't think the eyes of this great detective,
Kogoro Mori, can be deceived!
You're wrong.
This has nothing to do with that!
Liar!
This is evidence that shouldn't be moved...
Ala?
A cat?
There seemed to be something wrong
with him, so I came to check on him.
Please! Don't tell anyone.
That high school student boy...
You called him Kudo-kun, right?
Eh? Ah, yes. Kudo Shin'ichi.
Could it be...
...that you love him?
Huh?!
What is this out of the blue?
It's nothing like love really.
He's such a detective geek.
Really? In that case, it's fine, but...
"Irresolution causes
the greatest harm," they say.
Eh... "Irresolution"?
When you're indecisive
and can't make up your mind.
Ah...
That's irresolution, huh?
When it comes to love...
I wonder if it's when you don't say
what should be said...
...and when you don't do
what you should do and then regret it?
Sir, you're a detective, aren't you?
A great detective.
It's a problem if you forget my name.
Um... I... might know who the criminal is.
Huh?!
What's that?!
This great detective, Kogoro Mori,
will now tell you!
The one and only truth!
Like I thought...
The criminal is you!
Sir...
Of course you can tell us your reason?
It's as obvious as Maeda Atsuko-chan!
(member of AKB48 and an actress)
She is in their top rank.
So green and immature...
You wouldn't know this...
...but this man caused a similar incident
using the same trick one month ago!
"Then... I'll go second!"
"Kazuyo, you go ahead."
"Then..."
"...I'll take two."
"Two!"
"One."
"Three!"
"Then I'll take 3 as well!"
"One."
"Two."
"I'll take two, too."
"I lost, didn't I?"
"Too bad!"
"Here. Your penalty game."
"You don't have to drink it."
"Kazuyo, are you okay?!"
"Kazuyo?! Are you okay?!"
Fortunately it wasn't anything that put
Kazuyo-san's life in danger.
Kazuyo-san was famous for trying to get
nominated for the No. 1 spot...
...but this guy from some time before had
wanted the nomination switched to Kumi-chan.
And so you tried to kill Kazuyo-san
for interfering with that.
That's right, isn't it?
Ah, truly nasty.
And then it appeared that
Kumi-chan had gotten it.
However, turned out this guy's money
was all Kumi-chan was interested in.
Now this time he got angry at
Kumi-chan and killed her!
That's right, isn't it?
The cocktail Kazuyo-chan drank...
...was a Salty Dog.
What about it?
She has high blood pressure and she normally
has to take anti-hypertension drugs...
In other words, she was taking pills
to lower her blood pressure.
Could it be...
Kazuyo-san had an interaction?
As expected. That's correct.
Don't... Don't ignore me.
What's the recipe for a Salty Dog?
Vodka and...
- Grapefruit juice!
- Right!
Grapefruit juice...
...when drunk in conjunction with certain types
of drugs, can strengthen their effectiveness...
...and make them dangerous.
Dangerous?
Could it be Kazuyo-san's...
blood pressure fell too much and...
She lost consciousness.
"Who on earth is it?"
"And for what reason?"
Have you had
high blood pressure for some time?
Yes.
So... I can't fail to take these each day.
We've heard that recently you played
a game with Mine-san and then collapsed...
"Irresolution causes the greatest harm," huh...
What did you say just now?!
Eh? Ah... Irresolution.
When you can't make up your mind...
"Irresolution causes the greatest harm..."
Who told you that quote?
Huh? Ah... I learned it earlier
from Kazuyo-san...
...but I didn't know what
the word "irresolution" meant...
I see...
The answer to this murder equation...
I know what the one and only truth is.
Sorry for keeping you waiting.
Kudo-kun...
Are you suspicious of me, too?
There's one thing I really wanted to ask you.
Go ahead.
That game one month ago
where Kazuyo-san collapsed.
Did you know it was Kazuyo-san
who suggested she play that game?
Eh?!
"Kanpai."
"Since Mine-sensei loves that game so much,
I'm sure to rise."
"Yes. Then, do you want to challenge Kumi?"
"Yeah."
The one who chose the penalty game
of a cocktail was also Kazuyo-san.
"Kumi"
"Then, a Salty Dog, please."
Why would she do such a dangerous thing?
Didn't Kazuyo-san want to
play that game as a test?
A test? Of what?
Your feelings.
Kazuyo-san was aware of the dangers in the test.
What would be Mine-san's choice?
Would it be Kumi-san?
"If you let me win,
I'll go out with you anywhere afterwards."
You immediately understood
the underlying rule of that game.
So you could somehow
turn the win over to her.
Since you knew about
the drugs she was taking...
...Kazuyo-san believed you wouldn't
deliberately allow her to lose.
However, the one Mine-san chose...
...was Kumi-san.
The criminal who killed Kumi-san...
You already know who that is, don't you?
The criminal is... you.
Kazuyo...
Mine-san said it.
That the hypertension drugs
you were taking were tablets.
But the ones you have today
are capsules, aren't they?
The poison is inside those capsules, isn't it?
- Takagi-kun, confirm that.
- Roger.
It was Descartes that made me realize
the relationship between you and Mine-san.
Descartes? What's that?
Rene Descartes.
A great mathematician that I admire.
"Only reason makes us human."
"Doubt is the beginning of knowledge."
Those are both quotes from Descartes.
And...
So is the quote Kazuyo-san told Ran.
"Irresolution is the cause of the greatest harm."
Yes. That's also a quote from Descartes.
Kazuyo-san, didn't you eagerly
study mathematics...
... in order to follow along with
Mine-san's conversations?
"Merry Christmas!"
"Ah, Kazuyo-chan..."
"What is that?"
"Ah, it's nothing..."
"You could say...
it's a direct coordinate system..."
"You could also call them
Cartesian coordinates..."
"They were created by Descartes,
but they're also called Cartesian coordinates..."
"Because I'm stupid,
I didn't do well in math..."
"Ah... That's okay!"
"Compared to human relationships,
mathematics is easy to understand."
"Please teach me more."
Ever since I had started at this job...
...there wasn't anyone who had
talked to me so seriously like he did.
I just...
...wanted to keep up with him.
Kazuyo...
And so she thought up this crime.
Kazuyo-san. To you, it didn't matter who it was
that ended up as number 16, did it?
What's more, you could say you didn't care...
...if it was Mine-san or Ran's father
who gave the wine to Kumi-san.
Whoever had the 16th spot with the poison in it,
Kumi-san, in the 20th spot, was sure to drink it.
That was all that was
important to you, Kazuyo-san.
Killing Kumi-chan...
Was that your goal in doing that?
Resentment for the one who took
the man you loved away...
That was your motive, right?
There was nothing I could do if he chose
a woman more beautiful than I.
I'm used to that happening...
Then why Kumi-chan?
By chance, I overheard her.
"That Sensei's loaded..."
"...so whether to Italy or Paris,
anywhere we wanna go'll be fine, Kenji."
"I think I'll have him cough up
all the funds for a nice apartment, too."
Such a dirty trick to play on Mine-san...
I never wanted him to hear that.
I thought, "I never want him to have to
go through such a bad time."
In order to protect Mine-san...
You killed Kumi-san?
Like the game one month ago
where Mine-san made his decision...
I decided, too.
Why...?
Why would you kill someone for my sake...
I'm the bad one...
"Only reason makes us human."
I'm sorry you went to
all the trouble to teach me that.
I guess it's because I am stupid after all...
Kazuyo...
I'm sorry...
"Kumi"
"Kazuyo"
Sir.
Why do you think Kazuyo-san would do that?
Rather than murder,
wouldn't there have been a much easier way...
You said it earlier, didn't you?
For the sake of the man she loved...
...she studied mathematics
with all her might, didn't she?
She wanted to be of use to him
at the end, no matter what...
That's how it was.
Why?
By doing that,
he'd remember her all his life...
Even if you're called a great detective,
I guess you are still a kid, huh?
Don't think that everything comes
with a clear explanation.
Humans aren't mathematics.
Do you know what the most troublesome thing
in people that can't be calculated is?
What's that?
A woman's heart.
Huh?
What about you, Shin'ichi?
In order to protect someone
you loved, would you kill?
No matter what the reason is...
...murder is murder.
"Descartes"
Boy detective! Counting on you!
Sir!
Ran, don't die!
You'd better not die, Ran!
Ran!
Ran.
I wouldn't kill someone for your sake.
But...
I would NEVER let one I loved die.
Ran! Are you okay?!
Shin'ichi...
Where's Dad?
He was shut in the room over there.
Eh?!
A balloon?
What on earth is this...
Whoever you are, stop it already!
Stop this balloon!
"Sonoko is Kidnapped!"
"What Lurks Behind
The Beautiful Sister's Inheritance Quarrel"
"This Drama is Fiction"